export const flashcards = [
  {
    front: "The House Money Effect",
    back: `The House Money Effect is a behavioral finance phenomenon where individuals are more willing to take risks with money they've won or gained, as opposed to their own original investment. This is based on the perception that "house money" (or profits) isn't as valuable as their own initial funds, even though economically, all money is equivalent.
`,
    tips: `In investing, this effect often manifests after a period of gains:
Increased Risk Appetite: Investors might become more comfortable taking high risks with recent gains, reasoning that they’re "playing with the house’s money" and can afford losses.
Less Caution After Gains: After a profitable trade or period of good returns, investors may become less risk-averse, engaging in speculative or high-risk investments, believing they can “afford” to lose what they’ve just gained.
Reduced Focus on Fundamentals: The sense of security from previous gains may lead investors to make decisions based on short-term momentum rather than long-term fundamentals or solid financial analysis.
Although it can provide a psychological buffer, the house money effect can lead to poor decision-making by distorting the perception of risk, often resulting in unbalanced portfolios or heightened exposure to volatility.
`,
  },
  {
    front: "Enmeshment Bias",
    back: `*Definition:* Blurred boundaries between individuals in relationships, often leading to over-involvement in each other’s affairs.`,
    tips: `*Tips:*
- Establish clear financial boundaries.
- Encourage financial independence.

*Finance Relevance:* Can lead to poor financial decisions due to lack of personal financial autonomy.`,
  },
  {
    front: "Prospect Theory",
    back: `*Definition:* The idea that the investors place more weight on perceived gains than perceived losses`,
    tips: ` **Examples:**
      1. An investor prefers avoiding a loss to acquiring an equivalent gain, leading to risk-averse behavior.
      2. A person makes decisions based on perceived gains and losses rather than final outcomes, like choosing a sure gain over a probable larger one.
    - **Tips to Remember:**
      - Picture weighing losses more heavily than gains.
      - Remember: "Losses loom larger than gains" – people value avoiding losses more than acquiring equivalent gains.`,
  },
  {
    front: "Disposition Effect",
    back: `Actual trading behavior, tendency to sell winners and hold losers. Impact is seen in portfolio management and performance - “locking in gains” and waiting for losers to rebound. TRADING PATTERN. Selling winners and holding losers. Locking in 10% gain but holding on to a stock that lost more than 10% hoping it will rebound.`,
    tips: `Examples: 
1. An investor sells a winning stock too early to "lock in gains" but holds onto losing stocks too long.
      2. A person keeps an underperforming mutual fund, hoping it will eventually recover, while selling successful ones.
   
 - **Tips to Remember:**
      - Think of "picking flowers and watering weeds."
      - Remember: "Don’t cut your winners short" – let profitable investments run.`,
  },
  {
    front: "Overreaction Bias",
    back: `Overreaction bias is a cognitive bias where investors respond too strongly to new information, often causing asset prices to deviate from their intrinsic values. 

When individuals experience overreaction bias, they place excessive weight on recent news or events while underestimating long-term factors, leading them to make impulsive investment decisions.`,
    tips: ` 1. An investor sells off their entire portfolio after a single market downturn, fearing a prolonged crash.
      2. A person rushes to buy a stock after one piece of good news, expecting sustained gains.
    - **Tips to Remember:**
      - Picture a knee-jerk reaction.
      - Remember: "First impulses aren’t always right" – don’t make hasty decisions based on initial reactions.`,
  },
  {
    front: "Recency Effect / Recency Bias",
    back: `*Definition:* The tendency to weigh recent events more heavily than earlier events.`,
    tips: `**Examples:**
      1. An investor bases their decision on the most recent financial news, ignoring long-term data.
      2. A person overweighs the last few months’ performance when evaluating an investment.
    - **Tips to Remember:**
      - Picture the latest song stuck in your head.
      - Remember: "Newest isn’t always truest" – recent information can overshadow the broader picture.`,
  },
  {
    front: "Availability Heuristic",
    back: `*Definition:* The availability heuristic is a mental shortcut that leads people to make decisions based on how easily examples or memories come to mind rather than on objective data or broader analysis. This heuristic is based on the assumption that if something is easily recalled, it must be important or likely to occur, even though that’s not always the case.`,
    tips: ` - **Examples:**
      1. An investor recalls a recent high-profile bankruptcy and overestimates the risk of other companies failing.
      2. A person overestimates the risk of plane crashes because of vivid news reports, leading to avoidance of air travel.
    - **Tips to Remember:**
      - Picture easy-to-recall examples dominating your thoughts.
      - Remember: "Ease of recall skews perception" – don’t let memorable examples distort risk assessment.`,
  },
  {
    front: "Illusion of Control Bias",
    back: `*Definition:*  Overestimating the ability to control events and outcomes that are actually BEYOND their control.`,
    tips: `**Examples:**
      1. An investor believes they can predict market movements and overtrades, increasing risk.
      2. A person feels they can influence lottery outcomes by choosing "lucky" numbers.
    - **Tips to Remember:**
      - Picture someone rolling dice with extra concentration.
      - Remember: "False sense of control" – overestimating influence over uncontrollable events.
*Finance Relevance:* Can cause overtrading or excessive risk-taking in investments and exhibits overconfidence . Attribute past investment successes to their own abilities, ignoring the role of chance or market conditions.`,
  },
  {
    front: "Overconfidence Bias",
    back: `*Definition:* The tendency to overestimate one's knowledge, skill, or ability.`,
    tips: `**Tips To Remember:**

- Be humble and realistic about your capabilities.
- Seek second opinions.

*Finance Relevance:* Can lead to excessive risk-taking and trading.`,
  },
  {
    front: "Self-Attribution Bias",
    back: `*Definition:* The tendency to attribute successes to oneself and failures to external factors.`,
    tips: `**Tips To Remember:**
    - Evaluate decisions objectively.
- Accept responsibility for both successes and failures.

*Finance Relevance:* May lead to overconfidence and riskier investment behavior.`,
  },
  {
    front: "Financial Infidelity",
    back: `*Definition:* Concealing financial information from a partner that could affect joint financial decisions.`,
    tips: `*Tips:*
- Maintain open communication.
- Share financial goals and status regularly.

*Finance Relevance:* Can lead to mistrust and poor financial planning in relationships.`,
  },
  {
    front: "Hoarding",
    back: `*Definition:* Accumulating items excessively and having difficulty discarding them.`,
    tips: `*Tips:*

- Set clear financial goals.
- Regularly review and declutter possessions.
*Finance Relevance:* Can result in excessive spending and poor investment decisions due to emotional attachment to possessions.`,
  },
  {
    front: "Financial Enabler",
    back: `*Definition:* Providing financial support to someone in a way that prevents them from becoming financially independent.`,
    tips: `*Tips:*
- Encourage responsible financial behavior.
- Set limits on financial support.

*Finance Relevance:* Can hinder financial growth and independence of the recipient.`,
  },
  {
    front: "Collectivism",
    back: `*Definition:* Prioritizing group goals over individual goals.`,
    tips: `*Tips:*

- Balance group needs with personal financial goals.
- Make joint financial decisions carefully.

*Finance Relevance:* Can influence financial decisions in family or group contexts.`,
  },
  {
    front: "Anchoring",
    back: `Anchoring is a cognitive bias where individuals rely heavily on an initial piece of information (the "anchor") when making decisions, even if it is irrelevant or arbitrary. Once set, the anchor can influence how people adjust their estimates or expectations, leading them to make decisions that may not fully reflect current or comprehensive information.`,
    tips: `*Tips:*
In finance, anchoring can affect investment decisions in several ways:
Stock Price Anchoring: Investors might fixate on a stock's historical high or the price at which they first purchased it. For example, if they bought a stock at $100, they might anchor on that price, feeling reluctant to sell below it even if the company’s outlook has worsened.
Earnings Forecasts: Analysts may use past earnings as a baseline and fail to adjust enough for changing economic conditions or company performance, leading to inaccurate forecasts.
Market Trends: Investors often anchor on recent market highs or lows, assuming these levels represent "normal" prices. This can cause overconfidence in a bullish market or undue caution after a market decline.
To mitigate anchoring, it's helpful to consciously seek diverse perspectives, consider multiple valuation methods, and continually update beliefs with new data. By doing so, investors can avoid decisions overly rooted in outdated or irrelevant anchors.`,
  },
  {
    front: "Money scripts",
    back: `Money scripts describes a story someone tells himself or herself about what is normal, expected, or desired in the context of money and personal finances; are learned behaviors and preferences that move you through the world, and they greatly impact your financial decisions. A person’s views, attitudes, and belief system about money shape the way they
approach, discuss, and further their financial vision.

In a 2011 Journal of Financial Planning article, Klontz et. al defined 4 categories of money scripts:
1. money avoidance,
2. money vigilance,
3. money worship, and
4. money status.`,
  },
];
